Daniel Lew

Toronto, Canada

Profile

I'm a Software Engineer based in Toronto, Canada. I'm a co-creator of Stagehand ☑, a drop-in review apps service for frontend applications. I have multiple years of experience with both the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems. I am also comfortable with cloud services such as AWS.

Skills

Backend Node.js, Express, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, PostgreSQL,

MongoDB, RESTful APIs

Frontend

JavaScript, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, JQuery

Tooling

Git, Linux, VPS

Cloud

AWS, Digital Ocean, Heroku

Professional Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Stagehand □

2020 - present

- Co-created Stagehand, an open-source review apps service for frontend applications
- Prototyped and built the infrastructure needed by stitching together AWS and GitHub Actions
- Utilized GitHub Actions to automatically set up and tear down review apps in response to events
- Designed cloud infrastructure on AWS to host frontend review apps
- Implemented review apps wrapper to provide customizable dashboard using Service Workers and clientside code.
- Built an intuitive CLI for the user-interface and collaboration across multiple devices
- Co-authored Stagehand's case study: Stagehand ☑
- Collaborated daily with a fully remote team of engineers

Full-stack Web Developer, Self-Employed

2018 - present

- Mello: Trello-like collaboration board built with Rails and React/Redux
- Water Scheduler: Keep track of your plants, built with Ruby and Sinatra
- World Chat: Multi room chat app over websockets hosted on a VPS, built with Node.js/React
- Request Bucket: Request Bin-like tool to receive and inspect request payloads, built with Express JS, MongoDB, and PostgreSQL. Set up on a VPS
- Project Manager: Rails API to manage projects, users, and auth, with an RSpec test suite.

Event Manager, Oliver & Bonacini

2015 - 2020 | Toronto, Canada

Managing massive, high-end events such as TIFF, Human Right Watch, Wedluxe.

Education

Launch School 2018 - 2020

Multi-year full-stack Software Engineering curriculum, mastery-based learning Ruby, JavaScript, SQL, HTTP, HTML, CSS | launchschool.com/employers ☑

Marketing Management, Humber College □

2015 - 2016 | Toronto, Canada

Psychology and Sexuality, Marriage, and Family **Studies,** University of Waterloo □

2008 – 2013 | Waterloo, Canada